cabelasclubvisa.com 2019-05-18

# Privacy Policy : Cabela's

**Table of Contents**

What Information We Collect  
Automated Online Information Collection

Tracking technologies and how we use them  
Cookies  
Ad Networks  
Social Media  
Website Analytics  
Google Analytics Advertising Features  
Mobile Website and App Data Collection

Other Tech Resources  
Third Party Websites  
"Do Not Track" Technologies

How the Information We Collect is Used  
How the Information We Collect is Shared  
How We Protect the Information We Collect  
The Choices Regarding the Information You Collect

Information About the CLUB® Program

Changes to This Privacy Policy  
Children  
Right to Removal of Posted Information - California Minors  
Your California Privacy Rights

Contacting Us

Frequently Asked Questions about Cabela's Privacy Policy

Last updated January 17, 2018

This privacy policy applies to [www.cabelas.com](https://www.cabelas.com/) and other technology resources owned and operated by Cabela's LLC ("Cabela's", "we", "us", "our") such as Cabela's online store, mobile applications, social platforms, chat rooms, and the like ("Tech Resources"), and to information collected when you visit our stores or otherwise communicate or interact with Cabela's outside of the Tech Resources. This privacy policy describes how Cabela's collects and uses the information you provide and the information that we otherwise collect. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our collection and use of your information and how you can access and update this information. 

If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at privacy@cabelas.com or by contacting us by postal mail at the address below.  If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the web site, www.cabelas.com and not through other means although we apply the same protections explained in this privacy policy. 

**Cabela’s LLC**  
**Privacy Compliance**  
**One Cabela Drive**  
**Sidney, NE 69160**  

WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT  
When you visit Cabelas.com, make use of Cabela's Tech Resources or visit us, whether at our retail locations, at trade shows or elsewhere, or otherwise contact us through phone or email, you may be asked to provide us with information in order for us to provide you with the products or services that you have requested. This information may include:

  * Name
  * Shipping and billing addresses
  * Date of birth
  * Email address
  * Phone number
  * Credit card number or other payment-related information

In addition, if you're applying for a CLUB Card, we may collect additional personal information that you provide as part of the credit card application. 

If you request one of our newsletters or send an inquiry to one of our customer service representatives, we will also store a record of your request along with your email address. When you order a giftcard or eGiftCard you are given the opportunity to include the name and a message for the recipient. We record this information, along with the shipping information. This information is only used for the sole purpose of completing your request or for whatever reason it may have been provided. 

We may enhance your customer profile and combine information you send us with other generally or publicly available information from third party vendors and data brokers to help us identify your preferences and interests and to help us complete and verify your contact and demographic information. 

Automated Online Information Collection  
For each visitor to our Tech Resources, our web server automatically recognizes where possible the web site or email (and associated email address) referring you to our Tech Resource. In order to monitor and improve our Tech Resources as well as personalize your experience with Cabela's through direct online advertising, our web servers track various other technical details about your visit, such as your computer's Internet protocol (IP) address, operating system, browser information, device type, internet service provider (ISP), date/time stamp, clickstream data and which Cabela's pages you visit. This information is collected and stored using a variety of common technologies such as cookies, web beacons, tags and log files. We use this data to gather analytics and to participate in ad networks. Learn more about our automated online information collection, tracking technologies and how to manage them. 

This website uses Mouseflow, a third-party analytics tools, to track page content and click/touch, movement, scroll, and keystroke activity. You can opt-out at: <https://mouseflow.com/opt-out>.

TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES AND HOW WE USE THEM

We and our partners use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users' movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. 

COOKIES  
A cookie is a block of text placed in a file on the user's hard drive by a web site you've visited. These types of cookies cannot identify an individual user specifically, such as by name or address. We use both first party cookies, and as set forth below in more detail, third party cookies. 

Cabela's uses first party cookies to observe visitor's navigation throughout our web site. Cabela's also has the ability to tie cookies to an individual through online registration and purchase information. This helps us identify ways to improve the shopping experience, personalize our web site, and collect information to provide direct online advertising.

Cabela's also uses both session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies are only used to track your browsing session, while persistent cookies are used to identify you when you come back to the Tech Resource in a different browsing session. For example, our shopping cart cookie is a persistent cookie, saved for a designated period of time in case the users' session expires and they return to complete a purchase within that time frame. 

If you do not want to use cookies, this will not prevent you from accessing the Cabela's Tech Resource. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers may provide information on how your browser may be configured so that cookies can be accepted with your permission or completely blocked. You may be able to change your browser settings so that they do not allow cookies to be accepted or saved at any time. You can also delete cookies that have already been saved at any time. Kindly note however that if you decline cookies, some functions on the website may be limited or unavailable.

AD NETWORKS  
We use third party ad networks (called third-party ad servers or network advertisers) including Google, Conversant, and various social media platforms (as discussed below) to deliver ads to you on our behalf. These third party ad networks may place their cookies, web beacons, pixel tags or other technology on the Website or the Application or in your browser to collect non-personal information about you when you visit this Website or use this Application (such as browser type, time and date, browsing or transaction activity, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over, or a platform-provided identifier during your visits to this and other websites) to enable those third party ad networks to deliver to you advertisements on third party websites and mobile applications for our products or services or those of third parties that are likely to be of greater interest to you. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis.

If you wish to Opt-out of Conversant please click here: [http://dtmc.cabelas.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=2122&cname=Cabelas&cmagic=abdbeb&clogo=2122.png&loc=us&lang=en-us](http://dtmc.cabelas.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=2122&cname=Cabelas&cmagic=abdbeb&clogo=2122.png&loc=us&lang=en-us)

We encourage you to view the privacy policy of advertisers and ad services to learn more about their cookies and other technologies. If you do not want to receive those kinds of advertisements, look for the "Ad Choices" icon in the advertisements, which will contain a link to the privacy policy of the ad network that will provide you with information on how to opt-out of receiving such targeted advertising. **You can also visit the website<https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices> or <https://www.aboutads.info/choices/> to learn more about interest-based advertising and third party ad networks and to opt-out of receiving ads from ad networks. Please remember that changing your settings with certain browsers and ad networks will not carry your privacy choices across browsers and other ad networks.**

SOCIAL MEDIA  
Our Tech Resources may allow you to connect and share information with various social media platforms, such as Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and Pinterest. These features may require us to implement cookies, plug-ins and/or APIs provided by such social media platforms to facilitate the communications and features. We may share information that you provide us or that we may collect about your use of the Tech Resources with these platforms, which information becomes subject to their privacy and data policies. We encourage you to visit the privacy policies of these platforms for further information: 

Facebook's Data Policy at [ https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy](https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy)  
Instagram's Privacy Policy at [ https://www.instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/](https://www.instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/)  
Twitter's Privacy Policy at [ https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en](https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en)  
Pinterest's Privacy Policy at [ https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy](https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy)

In addition, by choosing to use any third party social media platform or choosing to share content or communications with any social media platform, you allow us to share information with the designated social media platform. We cannot control any policies or terms of such third party platform. As a result, we cannot be responsible for any use of your information or content by a third party platform, which you use at your own risk.

We may also use the advertising services and networks offered by these social media platforms, such as Facebook, Instagram, Pinterest and Twitter to deliver ad content. Use of these services requires the social media platform to implement cookies and/or pixels to deliver ads to you while online with such platforms. 

If you are a member of one of these networks but do not wish the operator to collect data relating to you via our Tech Resources, you can take the following steps:

Always log out completely from the network in questions before visiting other websites, and delete any related cookies, as the plug-in providers have represented to us that your personal details such as your IP address are only collected and processed when members are logged in to the social network;

Hide the plug-ins using an ad blocker; or

The platform may allow you to disable such interest based advertising, which you would need to investigate with the particular platform provider. For example, you may opt out of interest-based advertising on Twitter by notifying Twitter through one of the methods they describe online: [ https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405)

WEBSITE ANALYTICS  
Like many websites, we use a number of analytics and optimization vendors. These vendors, such as Google Analytics, Webtrends and Yahoo Analytics, collect information that your web browser automatically sends, such as the web address of the page that you visit and your IP address. These vendors may also set cookies or read preexisting cookies. This information is stored on the vendor's servers and the vendor uses this information to provide us with reports about traffic to our website and your visit to our website (such as the domain from which you access the internet, the web address of the website from which you linked to our site, the time and date of your visit to the web pages that you view and click through). We will use this data to improve our website structure and content.

Google may also use this data in accordance with their Privacy Policy, which can be found at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>. For more detailed information on how Google uses your data through our Site, please visit <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.

GOOGLE ANALYTICS ADVERTISING FEATURES  
We have also enabled the following Google Analytics Advertising Features: Google Display Network Impression Reporting, Remarketing with Google Analytics and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. The Google Display Network Impression Reporting uses the Google Analytics cookie to track our ad impressions and your interactions with those impressions, including the effectiveness of those ads, which generates reports for us to help us analyze our advertisements. Remarketing with Google Analytics uses the Google Analytics cookie to serve advertisements to you across the Internet based on your visit to our Web Site. Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting uses a third party cookie to collect information about our website traffic by tracking users across websites and across time, which generates a report for us to better understand our website users.

For the Google Analytics Advertising Features, you may also opt-out of our use of Google Analytics as described below. Please remember that changing your settings with certain browsers and ad networks will not carry your privacy choices across browsers and other ad networks.

MOBILE WEBSITE AND APP DATA COLLECTION  
If you access our mobile website or have downloaded our mobile app, we may also automatically collect information about the type of mobile device you use, your mobile device identifier, your mobile operating system, pages you visit on our mobile site, search terms, the type of mobile internet browsers you use and information about the way you use our mobile website and app. We use this information to obtain data about your visits to our stores, your general shopping habits, how you use our mobile platforms and how we might improve them.

If you choose to share your location with us, we use a service provider to approximate your position based on one or more of the following, as available: network location (cell tower triangulation) technology, GPS, wi-fi signals and/or Bluetooth signals. In addition, we may also send you push notifications based on your location if you activate your location settings on your device. IF YOU DO NOT WANT US TO HAVE ACCESS TO YOUR LOCATION, YOU MAY CHANGE YOUR LOCATION SETTINGS AS PERMITTED BY YOUR MOBILE DEVICE. CABELA'S HAS NO RESPONSIBILITY OR LIABILITY FOR THE FUNCTION OF THE LOCATION SETTINGS FEATURE WITHIN ANY MOBILE DEVICE.

Once you allow location based tracking through a mobile application or mobile website, you are agreeing that we can collect and use your location data and can continue to do so until you turn off your location settings and/or opt out of that usage, as may be permitted by your mobile device. We use this location based data to track your general shopping patterns and stores that you visit and we also aggregate this data to help understand general consumer patterns and trends.

OTHER TECH RESOURCES  
On certain portions of our Tech Resources, we provide entry forms for contests, sweepstakes and promotions. There are also mobile applications and other functions that are geared towards user mobility features such as status updates, check-in, and bragging rights, some which have geo-tagging features. It is important to understand that when you participate in these enhanced Tech Resources, much of the information you choose to provide is considered "public knowledge" and it is your responsibility to protect your own privacy. If you register to use any of these features, contests, promotions or sweepstakes, we will keep your information in accordance with this privacy policy and any additional terms and conditions applicable to or posted in connection with the contest, promotion or sweepstakes rules. These enhanced Tech Resources are provided without any warranty and you use them at your own risk. Cabela's reserves the right to approve or reject content uploaded by you.

If you create a wish list on our website, your profile will be publicly accessible unless otherwise indicated. You may change the privacy setting of your profile through your account portal.

THIRD-PARTY WEBSITES  
Our Tech Resources include links to other web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Cabela's. If you visit any third party sites or submit information to any of those web sites, your information is governed by their privacy policy. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any web site you visit.

"DO NOT TRACK" TECHNOLOGY  
As you may be aware, there are on-going discussions regarding "Do Not Track" technology. "Do Not Track" technology allows a user to choose in each separate browser environment (i.e. Internet Explorer, Chrome, Firefox, etc.) whether he or she wants his or her browsing to be tracked across websites. However, industry efforts to standardize "Do Not Track" technology and policies are ongoing. Since "Do Not Track" technology has not been fully standardized, we currently do not honor "Do Not Track" requests at this time. We will continue to monitor "Do Not Track" developments so that we can work towards honoring the preferences of our customers as efficiently as possible.

HOW THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT IS USED  
The information we collect is used to provide the products and services that you have requested and may be used to provide you information that we think you might have an interest in through marketing outreach to you directly or indirectly. It is also used to improve the content of our Tech Resources and to notify you about your order status. If you provide us with your postal address, you may receive periodic catalogs from us or others containing information about new products and services or upcoming events.

We may request your telephone number or facsimile (FAX) number, and if you provide it, you may receive telephone or FAX contact from us with information regarding your orders, requests for information or in reference to valuable offers from us. We do not sell or rent phone numbers.

If you provide us with a cell phone number and provide us your prior express written consent by opting-in, we will send you text messages to your mobile device. To opt out of a specific mobile messaging campaign at any time, reply "stop" to 247365. Your carrier's data and messaging rates may apply.

HOW THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT IS SHARED  
We will share your information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.

In order to operate our Tech Resources and in order to provide you with the products and services you have requested, we occasionally need to share information with third parties. We may transmit your information to service providers who may assist us with services such as processing orders, shipping products to you and processing your payment information. In addition, service providers help us with the services described in greater detail below. Their only role is to help us conduct our business. They are not permitted to use your information for any secondary purpose. We have agreements with these service providers and strive to ensure protection of your information by such service providers consistent with this Policy. Some of those organizations may have their own Privacy Policies which may give you additional protections, so you are encouraged to read those policies when presented to you.

We use software tools and service providers to help us gather and analyze information about our customers on our web site. By reporting and tracking ads served on our Tech Resources and providing additional information about our customers, these service providers help us conduct our business, optimize our ad campaigns, and deliver the most relevant products and services.

BrassRing is our service provider for tracking and processing job applications. No information is collected unless specifically entered by the user. This information is only used in connection with applying for a job at Cabela's. You may review BrassRing's privacy policy here or to have your information deleted from the career database, please email BrassRing at [swlegal@us.ibm.com](mailto:swlegal@us.ibm.com;).

We may make our postal mailing address lists available to subsidiaries and affiliated companies that are part of the Cabela's family of companies. We may also make our postal mailing address lists available to non-affiliated parties in order to offer you a Cabela's CLUB® credit card, and to direct mail companies who we believe may have products and services of interest to our customers. We do not share email addresses with any outside organizations that do not have operational relationships with Cabela's for their own marketing purposes.

If Cabela's is involved in a merger, acquisition, reorganization, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, customer information will likely be shared for evaluation purposes and included among the transferred assets. We may share any data within our databases and may transfer title to that data as part of any such transaction. Any successor in interest will remain bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy as it relates to your information.

If required by law, we may provide any and all information we have about you to law enforcement or other government agencies, pursuant to a subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings, warrant, or other order by a court of competent jurisdiction or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. In all cases, we will require written documentation of the request, proof of the identity of the law enforcement official making the request, and we will take steps to authenticate the validity of the request. Any law enforcement or government agency request submitted with less than a court-issued order will be evaluated on a case-by-case basis according to the need and urgency, as well as the particular law enforcement agency making the request.

HOW WE PROTECT THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT  
Cabela's strives to maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the integrity and confidentiality of your personal information. When you make a purchase on Cabelas.com we use technology to protect your order information before transmitting it to our secure server. Although such technology makes it difficult for anyone to intercept or misuse credit card or information, no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

In addition, our systems are also housed in secure facilities and access to your data by our employees is limited to a "need to know" basis, controlled by password protected systems, and monitored for unauthorized access.

If you are still unsure of giving your credit card over the Internet, please feel free to phone, fax, or mail your order to us. For telephone ordering or assistance, please call 1-800-237-4444. Our fax number for orders is 1-800-496-6329 (for US/Canada 1-308-254-2200). Or, send your order to:

Cabela's  
Attn: Order Processing  
One Cabela Drive  
Sidney, NE 69160

THE CHOICES REGARDING THE INFORMATION YOU COLLECT  
If you do not want to receive email from us, please let us know by calling, sending an email, opting out by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email you received from us or by writing to us at the above postal address and telling us that you do not want to receive email from our company. If you are a registered member at Cabelas.com, you may change your preferences in the My Account Section.

If you do not wish to receive postal mailings from Cabela's, its subsidiaries, or third-party organizations, please let us know by calling, sending an email, or writing to us at the above postal address. Please provide us with your exact name and postal address and state which lists you wish to be removed from so that we can be sure your information is removed from future mailing lists.

When you download a mobile application from us, we have the ability to use a service provider to provide you with push notifications containing marketing messages to your mobile device. Your device may allow you to opt out of these push notifications by accessing your device's application or notification settings for the Cabela's app. Cabela's has no control over the application permission notifications that may be provided to you on download from a third party app store or the ability of your device to opt-out of these push notifications.

You may opt-out of our use of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Analytics opt-out page and installing the Google Analytics browser add-on, currently made available by Google at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

You may opt out of Yahoo's collection of analytics information outside of the Yahoo distribution network, by clicking on the following link: [https://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/opt_out/targeting/details.html.](https://info.yahoo.com/privacy/us/yahoo/opt_out/targeting/details.html)

If you choose to opt-out of our use of your information for direct marketing purposes, this does not remove your information from our data database entirely. We will retain your information to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. In addition, if you include your email in an order, you will continue to receive transactional messaging about your order status.

If you are a registered user of the web site, you can manage many aspects of your registration information. If your information changes, you may correct or update the information by making the changes on our member information page. For security reasons, however, some parts of your information may not be changed online and may require you to call or write to us in order to verify your identity before such changes can be made. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. To request that we no longer use your information to provide our services, the removal of your testimonial, or the removal of your information from a blog or public forum, please contact us via our [Customer Service email address](mailto:https://cabelas.custhelp.com/app/ask;).

INFORMATION ABOUT THE CLUB® PROGRAM  
The Cabela's CLUB card is issued by Capital One Bank (USA), N.A. ("Capital One"). When you apply for a Cabela's CLUB card, we submit your information to Capital One. To view Capital One's privacy notice, please [click here](https://www.capitalone.com/media/doc/corporate/english-privacy-notice.pdf). We may also share your information with Capital One or its designated service providers in order to offer you a Cabela's CLUB Credit card. Communications related to these offers are monitored for quality and compliance purposes such that the individuals and vendors monitoring these communications may also receive access to the information shared as part of such offers.

CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY  
We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.

CHILDREN  
Our website and other Tech Resources are not directed at children. In accordance with federal law, we do not solicit or knowingly collect information from children under age 13 without the verifiable permission of a parent or guardian. If Cabela's learns that a child under the age of 13 has submitted information online without parental consent, it will not use such information for any purpose (except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required or allowed by law) and will take all reasonable measures to delete such information from its databases by identifying such information for a purge process. If you become aware of any information we have collected from children under 13, please contact us as provided below.

RIGHT TO REMOVAL OF POSTED INFORMATION - CALIFORNIA MINORS  
If you are under 18 years of age, reside in California, and have a registered account with Cabela's, you have the right to request removal of unwanted information that you publicly post on the Tech Resources. To request removal of such information, you can contact Cabela's as provided below. Upon receiving such a request, Cabela's will make sure that the information is not publicly available on the Tech Resources, but the information may not be completely or comprehensively removed from our systems and databases.

**YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**  
**This Privacy Policy describes how we may share your information for marketing purposes. You may contact us with any questions and, to the extent applicable, to request a list of third parties to whom we may disclose information for marketing purposes and the categories of information we may disclose.** CONTACTING US  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy and Cabela's policies and practices with respect to personal information, please contact us at:

Cabela's LLC  
Privacy Compliance  
One Cabela Drive  
Sidney, NE 69160  
privacy@cabelas.com
